let's look at the solution to our
prefetch instructions squiz let's look
first at this Inner Loop and the
prefetch distance for fetching elements
of the B array we were told that each
iteration takes two 10 Cycles if there
are no misses and we want to eliminate
misses so if we do prefetching correctly
there will be 10 cycles per iteration
here the Miss penalty and the memory
latency are 200 Cycles which means that
we should be ising a prefetch for a b
element and 200 Cycles before we reach
it
corresponds to 20 iterations so we will
prefetch 20 iterations ahead of time and
we will do it because if we do it this
way the prefetch will arrive just in
time for B to get its value now we need
to figure out what to prefetch here and
whether we should be doing the
prefetching we should not be doing the
prefetching if by the time we we reach
the axis to that element of a know that
this should be I + 1 or something larger
this eliminates that element from the
cache so the question is how much cache
stuff does each iteration of this outer
loop bring in and the answer is it
brings 1,00 8 by elements here and an
element of a so if we prefetch with a
distance of one what we get is that our
pre prefetch is done after 200 Cycles
there are 10,000 Cycles here so it's in
time to be accessed in the next
iteration of the outer loop the question
is just does this element get kicked out
before we can use it and the answer is
no because 8 times this 1,000 ends up
being 8,000 the cache is 16 kiloby so
basically if we prefet here the element
of the AR array that we prefet will
still be there when we eventually get to
the next iteration of the outer loop
where we get to use it so the answer is
we should prefetch with I + 1 and we
should not be selecting this note that
we should not be prefetching with I + 20
here if we do that there are 20 Loops in
between when we prefetch and when we
actually use it and each of these Loops
is bringing in 8,000 bytes worth of B so
if we prefetch that early
then 20 * 8 is larger than our cash and
the element we prefetch would be kicked
out from the cash so that would be an
example of premature prefetching